Gentry Smith

M.S. COMPUTATIONAL CHEMISTRY · AUTOMATION CONSULTANT

915 E Warner Ave Guthrie, OK 73044

□ 913-231-3282 | iamgentrysmith@gmail.com

Summary.

Over three years graduate experience in data analysis, tool automation, and computational methods. Over seven years experience in various programming languages and the Linux environment. Passionate about solving problems with automation and developing new tools to improve user workflow.

Education

Oklahoma State University

Stillwater, OK

June. 2016 - Dec. 2018

M.S. IN CHEMISTRY

- Emphasis in computational methods.
- Research emphasis on structural conformation prediction and optimization in tetravalent systems.
- Recipient of the Coloney Whiteley Scholarship for outstanding graduate students at the master's level.

Southern Nazarene University

Bethany, OK

B.S. IN CHEMISTRY

Aug. 2012 - May. 2016

- Minor in biology.
- Course emphases in physics and computer science.

Technical Skills_

- Python 2, Python 3, Java, R
- Bash, Git, VIM
- Microsoft Office, Apple iWork, Google Drive
- macOS, Windows, Linux, FreeBSD
- Agile, Test-Driven Development

Work Experience _

Self-Employed

Oklahoma City, OK

Jan. 2019 - Present

- **AUTOMATION CONSULTANT**
- Independent contractor providing custom automation solutions for repetitive and time-intensive workflow
- Involved creation and maintenance of software tools that interface with multiple programs to unify the user experience.
- Recent contract involved improving company workflow by 10% through automation tools.

Oklahoma State University

Stillwater, OK

GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT

Aug. 2016 - May 2019

- Assisted in teaching and grading responsibilities for general chemistry courses.
- Strengthened leadership and mediation skills as an intermediary authority between students and head professor.
- Average 4.65 / 5.00 rating on instructor evaluations.

Self-Employed

Oklahoma City, OK

COMPUTER SYSTEMS CONTRACTOR

June 2013 - Current

- As-needed computer specialist providing on-site tech support and customized hardware solutions for multiple medical clinics.
- Prioritized hardware purchases to provide a cost-effective solution and excellent end-user experience.

Writing

Exploring Critical Conformations: State Searching and Sampling in Both Germanium Chains and Ice Interfaces

Master's Thesis

Dec. 2018